northshore.edu 2008-12-17

# NSCC - Privacy Policy

**Welcome to the North Shore Community College (NSCC) Web site. Your privacy is one of our top priorities.** The following policy applies only to the use of NSCC’s Web site. Other Web sites operated by state agencies have different policies. NSCC suggests that you read the privacy policies for each Commonwealth Web site that you visit, and any external site that you visit through a link appearing at this site. NSCC is not responsible for the content of, or for the privacy policy of, or the use of personal information gathered at a Web site that you may visit through a link appearing at this site.

## A Privacy Relationship

Your privacy with respect to the use of this Web site results from a relationship between NSCC and you, the user. At this Web site, NSCC attempts to protect your privacy to the maximum extent possible. However, because some of the information that NSCC receives through this Web site is subject to the [Public Records Law, Massachusetts General Laws Chapter 66, Section 10](http://www.state.ma.us/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm) and [Chapter 4, Section 7(26)](http://www.state.ma.us/legis/laws/mgl/4-7.htm), NSCC cannot ensure absolute privacy. This policy informs you of the information that NSCC collects from you at this site, what NSCC does with it, to whom it may be disseminated, and how you can access it. Based on this information, you can make an informed decision about whether to share personally identifiable information with NSCC through this site.

## Definitions

Cookies are files that a Web site can place on your computer. A cookie file contains unique information that a Web site can use to track such things as your password, lists of Web pages you have visited, and the date when you last looked at a specific Web page, or to identify your session at a particular Web site. A cookie file allows the Web site to recognize you as you click through pages on the site and when you later revisit the site. A Web site can use cookies to "remember" your preferences, and to record your browsing behavior on the Web. Although you can prevent Web sites from placing cookies on your computer by using your browser's preference menu, disabling cookies may affect your ability to view or interact with some Web sites. 

An "Internet Protocol Address" or "IP Address" is a series of numbers that identifies each computer and machine connected to the Internet. An IP address enables a server on a computer network to send you the file that you have requested on the Internet. The IP address disclosed to NSCC may identify the computer from which you are accessing the Internet, or a server owned by your Internet Service Provider. Because it is machine-specific, rather than person-specific, an IP address is not, in and of itself, personally identifiable information. 

Personally Identifiable Information. NSCC uses the term "personally identifiable information" to mean any information that could reasonably be used to identify you, including your name, mailing address, e-mail address, Social Security number, birth date, bank account information, credit card information, or any combination of similar information that could be reasonably used to identify you. 

## Information Voluntarily Provided by You

This site collects voluntary information from you only through the e-mails and/or forms that you send through this site. E-mails and/or forms sent by you to this site will contain personally identifiable information. 

## Information Collected and Stored by this Site

This site does not collect "cookies", but may collect and store indefinitely your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, as well as information about the date and time of your visit, whether a file you have requested exists, and how many "bytes" of information were transmitted to you over the Web from this site. NSCC can use your IP address to assess the frequency of visits to this site and the popularity of its various pages and functions. NSCC will not attempt to match any personally identifiable information that you provide to NSCC with your IP address, unless there are reasonable grounds to believe that doing so may provide information that is relevant to or necessary as part of an investigation concerning the violation of a law or College policy. 

## Dissemination of Your Personally Identifiable Information

NSCC does not sell any personally identifiable information collected through this Web site. However, any personally identifiable information voluntarily submitted to NSCC through an e-mail or a form submittal is subject to the [Public Records Law](http://www.state.ma.us/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm) and the [Fair Information Practices Act (Massachusetts General Laws Chapter 66A)](http://www.state.ma.us/legis/laws/mgl/gl-66a-toc.htm), and other applicable laws and regulations. **For this reason, part or all of the information you send NSCC may be disclosed in response to a public records request.**

In addition, the information that you voluntarily submit will be disclosed only to Commonwealth employees or officials with a "need to know" for purposes of fulfilling their job responsibilities. These individuals will only use the information to answer your questions, respond to any requests for assistance, and fulfill the Commonwealth's legal obligations. Where appropriate, NSCC may provide the information submitted by you to the person or company that is the subject of your inquiry, or to a government agency responsible for the matters referred to in your communication. 

## Your Access and Opportunity to Correct

The [Public Records Law](http://www.state.ma.us/legis/laws/mgl/66-10.htm) and the [Fair Information Practices Act](http://www.state.ma.us/legis/laws/mgl/gl-66a-toc.htm) provide you certain rights to get information about you that is in our records. To learn more about the circumstances under which you can get and correct this information, please click on the above references to these laws. 

## Security

Because this site does not encrypt all incoming e-mail, you should not send information that you consider highly sensitive through this Web site. NSCC uses standard security measures to ensure that your personally identifiable information is not lost, misused, altered, or unintentionally destroyed. The Commonwealth also uses software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits. 

## Special Protections Against Misuse Of Personally Identifiable Information Within Commonwealth Offices

[Executive Order 412](http://www.state.ma.us/consumer/new/privexeco.htm) enhances the privacy protection of information about you as a named individual held by the Executive Department of state government. [Executive Order 412](http://www.state.ma.us/consumer/new/privexeco.htm) limits the collection and dissemination of personally identifiable information within the Executive Department. This site complies with [Executive Order 412](http://www.state.ma.us/consumer/new/privexeco.htm), so all of the personally identifiable information that you submit to this site is handled consistent with [Executive Order 412](http://www.state.ma.us/consumer/new/privexeco.htm). 

## Policy Changes

NSCC will post changes to this policy at least 30 days before they take effect. Any information NSCC collects under the current privacy policy will remain subject to the terms of this policy, consistent with the Public Records Law and the Fair Information Practices Act. After any changes take effect, all new information NSCC collects, if any, will be subject to the new policy. 

## Contact Information

For questions about your privacy while using this Web site, please contact NSCC’s Chief Information Officer Gary Ham at [gham@northshore.edu](mailto:gham@northshore.edu).
